Did you knock ' em dead Corky ?
I did everything right .
You mean it went perfect ?
You 're first time on your own .
Me not there to see .
Don 't make it more than it was .
Now don 't give me that inferiority crap .
Now , did the lift go okay ?
I never did it better .
Open .
Now , when you 're rich and famous ,
don 't you forget me .
I 'll never forget you .
Open .
There are not three guys alive
that can do what you can with those cards .
I 'm tellin ' ya kid ,
you 're as good as the game .
Sure , sure , sure .
Another Houdini .
Where you scared ?
I sure was when I started .
Well I wasn 't calm .
But then ,
I wasn 't all that worried .
I figured I 'd uh ...
done all the practicing I could so what the hell .
Were you the only magician ?
Yes sir .
The men all wanted to be Bob Dylan
and the girls did mostly Barbara Walters imitations
or sang Dolly Parton songs .
Some of them panicked
before they got up to perform .
Not you though ?
No , not me .
See , the guy who was in charge of everything
ran things so well .
He had one of those hourglass egg timers
and when he turned it over you started ,
and when the sand was finished
so were you .
Good evening .
Tell me kid ,
did you begin with some flourishes ?
Yeah .
You always taught me
that they were the best attention grabbers .
Was I , was I right ?
It was amazing .
Everybody quick shut up and watched .
No more whispering .
Nothing .
And once you had ' em Corky ,
then what did you do ?
Well I quick told this pudgy lady at the ringside
to please pick any card she wanted
as long as it was the big casino ,
the ten of diamonds .
Okay , would you please show the card to the audience ?
And I forced it on her perfectly .
Everybody loved it a lot and laughed .
And then I went straight into rising aces .
Did the lift work great ?
Yes sir .
The sand was really running out of that hourglass .
And I told myself to forget it
and just concentrate on the moves .
So I took my time and made it work
and everybody applauded like crazy .
So I just took a couple of bows
and I got off .
Oh kid .
Don 't bullshit me .
I really did do everything right .
Really .
Only nobody much cared .
And ?
Go on .
I guess I just cracked .
" You stupid sons of bitches , " I said , "
" Don 't you know how hard that was ? "
" That 's a thousand hours of my life you just saw . "
They don 't care from heart kid .
They just want to be entertained .
I guess I didn 't do you proud all in all .
But did you talk to the people ?
Did you use your charm ?
I can 't , and you know that .
Corky ?
You want to be
as good as the game .
Don 't you ?
You know I do .
Then you gotta find yourself
some charm kid .
How ?
You 'll think of something .
Hey man , why don 't you ...
Hi , I 'm George Todson , NBC .
I 'm to meet Mr. Ben Greene .
Oh , yes sir .
He 's right inside .
Thank you .
Say my man , how come he goes ahead of us ?
I guess this boy Withers
is your latest sensation , hmm ?
Oh yeah , sit down .
Yeah , since you booked him into a very classy spot Ben .
And I found him here .
You know , it 's not easy getting him to move .
You want a beer ?
It 's safe .
Sure .
He likes this place ?
Well , he bombed here
his first time out , you know ?
But he didn 't get ...
hey , get him a beer garcon .
Sure , Budweiser ?
But he didn 't give up .
He just worked his ass off for a year .
He come back .
And he hit it big .
There 's never been a magician like him .
You dragged me down here for a magician ?
Come on Ben .
I run a goddamn network .
We can 't book those guys
on kiddy shows anymore .
Now listen ,
your old man got his start working for me
you little fart .
Don 't tell me what bombs .
Magic is misdirection .
That 's all it is .
And misdirection is getting the people to look
in the wrong place at the right times .
So ?
So naturally ,
magic has had a little trouble on the tube .
Why ?
Because you can 't misdirect
the goddamn camera .
Ladies and gentlemen ,
a warm welcome for Mr. Corky Withers .
Good evening .
Ordinary deck of cards .
Loaded with stage presence .
I can 't decide ,
does he remind me more of Errol Flynn
or Valentino ?
Thank you .
Young lady , would you please pick any card you want ?
As long as it 's the big casino ,
ten of diamonds ?
Will you show the audience please ?
Dynamite opening Ben .
Does he actually get better ?
That 's hard to believe .
Well he got a little nervous
on account he knows we 're here .
My teacher was a great man .
His name was Merlin , and uh ...
No , seriously his name was Merlin , Jr . ,
and this is his version of the rising aces .
And here were are , here are the four aces .
One ,
two ,
three ,
four .
I 'm going to place them back on top of the deck .
And would you please pick any card ?
Just pick any card .
Good .
Look at the card , remember it ,
and cover the aces .
Thank you .
All right uh ...
I 'm sorry , I did that wrong .
You 're not supposed to cover the aces in this trick .
Um , I 'm sorry .
One sec .
He 's gonna pull a five card left .
Watch him ,
just watch him , will ya ?
Goddamn drunks .
He 's not liftin' just the top card .
He 's gonna grab five .
Sir , if you think you can do better ,
you 're welcome to try .
Just gimme a hand getting up there schmucko .
And step aside .
Okay , you 're on .
Okay .
What 's going on .
Thank you .
You really think you 're that good do you ?
I 'll guaran-fuckin ' - tee ya I am .
Thank you .
Ahhh ...
You ruined the rising aces .
So what , screw it .
You see the broad with the big jugs ?
You mean the ah , young lady in the feathers ?
Yeah , I see her so what ?
Wonder if she 'ld like a roll in the shavings with me ?
I don 't think you 're very funny .
Well they do .
Thank you .
A nice gimmick , the dummy .
What 's his name ?
Fats .
Don 't encourage him .
I will now change a diamond into a heart .
I guess the reason I 'm such a great lover is um ...
I don 't want to hear about your sex life
if you don 't mind .
Tell us all about yours then .
Everybody likes short stories .
Shhh , Don 't encourage him please ladies and gentlemen .
That 's really a clever shtick .
Thank you .
All right ,
pick a diamond .
Huh ?
I said pick a diamond .
All right .
It can change into a heart while I 'm holding it .
Well , go on , show the audience .
If you 're so great ,
change it while I 'm holding it .
You won 't give it back to me ?
Well that 's another trick you 've ruined .
Let 's see ,
I 'll just have to think of something else .
You mean you 're not gonna change my diamond into uh ...
Jesus Christ .
What ?
It turned into a heart
while I was holding it .
How 'd he do that ?
How did he do it ?
How many times do I have to tell you .
Do you want to get out of here alive ?
The kids good , I 'll give him that .
Sure he 's good .
I got me maybe the best magician in 50 years .
Team 'd with the first X-rated dummy on the block .
Eat your heart out .
You say he really bombed here first time ?
Yes .
Of course he didn 't have the dummy with him then .
The dummy helps .
No question .
Right .
Local talent ?
No .
He was brought up near Grossinger 's in the Catskills .
I think his old man was a limey .
Came here to work in a health club
and gave massages .
Somethin ' like that .
It 's me .
Chick , It 's old Gangrene .
Gangrene .
That 's funny .
Quick into .
Corky , our visitor from New York , George Todson .
How do you do sir ?
You have a lot of potential .
Hey what about me ?
You 're terrific too Fats .
Thanks Mr. Wigston ,
I mean Tubeston .
Todson .
Now that 's what I call funny .
Hey , you 'll strain your pacemaker .
Behave yourself .
Come here a second , will ya ?
Ah , by the way ,
how did you change the diamond to the heart ?
I 'm the misdirection dummy .
While we 're bullshitting ' ,
you could bring an elephant on to the stage .
Which is why this magician
will not bomb on the tube .
Why ?
Because the goddamn camera watches their faces
and not Corky 's hands .
So you live and you learn .
See ya .
Bye .
Yeah , all right .
How 'd it go ?
Sen-fuckin ' - sational .
See I 'm catching .
What happens next ?
Well , we reel ' em in slow .
The same kind of low key build up
we gave Steve Martin last year .
I 'm not lettin ' you near New York ,
till we 're close to making a deal .
So I just stay here ?
No , first , I 'd like to book you
in a small lounge in Vegas for the experience .
Then the area talk shows .
You know , Tom Snyder , Mike Douglas .
All leading to Carson .
And if he asks you to come back ,
I think he will ,
that should do it .
So , you keep motor mouth here in line ,
while I work on them
droolers at the network .
It should take five , maybe six months .
Now , when I buy you a free lunch
at the Four Seasons in New York ,
you 'll know you 're home free .
Sound okay ?
Yes sir .
You 're a good kid Corky .
Hey , you know what I think ?
No , what do you think ?
We 're gonna be a star .
Zachary !
Seems like I 'm breaking the law .
I 'll see that no one touches it sir .
No one must ever touch a Rolls , but a Rolls man .
Yes sir .
Margo , will you show this gentleman
to Mr. Greene 's table please ?
Hi .
Is everything all right ?
They want me ?
The uh , network people I mean .
May I ?
Yeah , thank you .
Have a cigar for later Corky .
Take two , they 're are big .
I invented conspicuous consumption .
Don 't you forget that .
If you 're trying to get my attention you got it .
Will you do me a favor kid ,
will you try not to turn shit heel .
It 's almost an automatic
once a guy makes it big .
I 'd love to see you beat the odds .
Maybe I won 't make it big .
Come on , tell me .
What is it .
Two years ago , you couldn 't get arrested .
Two years from now
you are going to have it all .
Corky , NBC wants a pilot special .
What 's that ?
What 's that ,
it 's what they gave Rich Little a while back .
Menu sir ?
Ah , you see , when they 're hot for somebody
like they 're hot for you ,
they make a contract which hinges on the first show .
And if it hits ,
you 're off and running for a bunch more .
Terrific .
That 's why they call me the Postman ,
I always deliver .
Is it set and , everything ?
It 's set but it 's not set , set .
There 's agent stuff like who pays how much for publicity ,
how much for the guest stars .
You 'll have to take a medical exam
and stuff like that .
Now what 's wrong .
Um ...
I don 't think I 'm going to take the medical exam .
Any particular reason .
Principle .
What the hell does that mean , principle ?
Do you remember that first night
when you came backstage at the uh , Stardust
and you said , you wouldn 't mind representing me .
Do you remember what I said ?
You 're goddamn right .
You said that I could represent you
but you didn 't want to sign .
That was principle too .
Because if we 're happy with each other ,
our word should be enough .
To hell with signing some piece of paper .
Why is this with the medical exam principle ?
Because they 're saying something wrong with me .
And I say I 'm fine .
I 'm fine .
I don 't need any doctors
poking around inside me that 's all .
Are you serious about this ?
I mean is this a deal breaker ?
Yeah , I guess it is .
Sadie , Sadie .
I have to put you on hold .
Sadie , what 's the first rule for being an agent ?
Never forget an act that killed Lincoln .
Head of the class .
Get me Bernstein in Legal .
Corky has turned impossible .
I don 't believe it .
Well , I should have been a cesspool cleaner
like my mama wanted .
Corky 's so cheap ,
last night he sent his girlfriend out to hustle .
It 's not true , not true .
Just ignore him .
When she came back this morning ,
he asked how much she 'd gotten and she said
" Sixteen dollars and ten cents " .
Corky said " ten cents ?
My God , who gave you ten cents ? "
And she said " Everybody " .
Dammit .
Everybody , she said ,
Body , body , body .
Dody , dudy , duny .
And she said ...
and she said everybody .
Hello ?
I 've been having meetings for hours .
I couldn 't budge ' em Cork .
I thought you said they wanted me ?
Well they do Cork , but ...
Didn 't you explain about the principle ?
Now kid , this is network policy .
It 's legal policy .
Now I 'm sitting here
with three of our genius lawyers ,
my God , their IQ 's alone
must total up to 100 .
Now we have called NBC a dozen times
and they are not ,
I repeat not about to spend
a half a million bucks
only to find out on taping day
that there 's some kinda health problem .
There 's no problem .
Corky !
Make ' em understand .
Well ...
shoo will you fellas .
Let me handle this alone .
Yep .
Good luck Ben .
Yeah .
Now kid I don 't have to ask you
what the trouble is .
'Cause I know what the trouble is .
I 've told you once before .
It 's just success kid .
Please believe me .
You want success
but you 're afraid of it .
Now that happens to everybody at this stage .
I 'm not afraid .
Now you stay right there .
and I 'll be right over
and we 'll talk it through .
I 'm not afraid .
Hang tight kid .
I 'm on my way .
I won 't be here .
We should hit Grossinger 's inside another 20 minutes .
Never mind that .
Take your next left .
Here .
Keep going into town .
Your place ?
I was brought up here .
Must remember it being a whole lot bigger huh ?
No .
Wanna look around .
No point .
Family all gone huh ?
Yeah .
Ah , you 're lucky .
I live with four brothers .
All assholes .
I don 't want to come on like some ghoul , but uh ...
do you got people in there ?
People ?
Just family .
You look a lot like yourself , you know that ?
Yeah , I caught you on the Carson Show a couple times .
You must make a ton for that huh ?
How 'd you luck into that ?
You know ?
See , I sing great .
I know they 'd cream over me .
My agent , William Morris , arranged it .
Is this Morris guy
a personal friend of Carson ?
Is that how that works ?
William Morris is the name of a agency , not a guy .
Oh .
Hold it , right here .
Pull over to your left .
Fine .
Hey , this is Lake Melody ain 't it ?
I 'll be right back .
Anybody ?
Anybody home ?
What do you want ?
A cabin .
We 're kinda closed .
Something above the lake is what I 'm after .
It 's just the kind of place I 'm looking for .
I won 't be disturbed here .
That 's for sure .
But like I said ,
we 're kinda closed .
$ 50 bucks a night .
In advance .
We just re-opened .
If you don 't want me waitin ' ?
How you gonna get to Grossinger 's ?
I 'll call a local cab when I need one .
How much ?
$ 80 bucks ,
not countin ' tip .
Okay .
Uh ...
Here 's a hundred for the driving ,
and another hundred ,
for a favor .
Name it .
You didn 't bring me here , okay ?
Okay .
Good .
Thanks .
What you see is what you get .
The um , the bedroom 's back there
and the kitchenette and the bathroom across .
Fine .
Here 's your key .
Help !
Calling all schmucko 's .
Save me .
Hi .
Jesus Christ .
This is Grossinger 's ?
I wonder if her ass is on ball bearings .
Shut up .
Oh , sounds like I stepped on a corn .
Sorry .
It 's just that I carried her picture all these years .
And she didn 't remember me .
Aw ...
He didn 't remember me .
Hello ?
Sorry to bother you .
Oh , that 's all right .
No soap .
I didn 't think you 'd like it .
You leaving now ?
No I didn 't mean no soap that way .
I meant there wasn 't any soap ,
or towels either .
Oh , come on in here and grab one .
Oh , oh my God ,
you brought Fats .
You thought Peg didn 't remember .
Aw ...
You knew who I was too ?
Yeah .
Well why didn 't you two
at least grunt at each other ?
He 's just as cute as he is on the tube ?
Cute ?
Virile yes .
Sexy yes .
Ronald Reagan is cute .
Oh please , could I hold him ,
I 'll be careful .
Oh , he 's heavy .
Husky you bimbo .
His lips didn 't move .
That 's because you 're not stroking my levers sweetheart .
Right in there .
Oh , she goosed me .
Ignore him , go right ahead .
Okay .
There .
And there .
I see .
I love it .
Hey , she hugged me to her bosom .
I suspect she found me irresistible .
Don 't we all ?
She asked you over for dinner , huh ?
How long are you going to stay ?
I don 't know , why ?
If you stayed late , that might mean
you was getting hugged to her bosom too
which just might make old Fats jealous
and we wouldn 't want that ,
would we now ?
Hmm ?
You never really told ,
why you were here .
I 'm hiding .
Gotta get my head on straight .
My agent ,
he looks like the Ancient Mariner
in that poem we hated in high school .
He 's negotiating for a shot for me
to maybe make it big .
We argued .
But I thought it was just principle .
The truth is probably I 'm scared of success .
That 's all .
You always were this
weirdly timid person Cork .
That 's for sure .
Your folks still run this place ?
No , they took a motel in Florida .
Gave this place to me .
But I just couldn 't make a go of it .
Too bad .
The Catskills are dying and that 's the truth .
Me and Duke are lookin ' to sell .
God , you 're beautiful .
Don 't I wish .
I had such a crush on you .
No one ever accused you of having good taste , Cork .
When I moved away I whittled you a present ,
a wooden heart .
You never gave it to me though .
I lost it before I got it finished .
I knew you had a crush on me .
I was always pretty for you .
I didn 't say pretty .
You didn 't pick up on my Duke mention either .
After all , he is my consort .
My spouse .
I 'm very big on enlarging my vocabulary .
Are you very big on Duke ?
We seem to separate what seems like ,
every full moon ,
it hasn 't been your everyday
Walt Disney type marriage .
Where is he ?
Quick business trip .
I 'm sorry .
Tell me , does he ...
does he still look like James Dean ?
Hey .
Hearty burgundy .
Very medicinal .
Peg ?
Admit it , now I 'm beautiful .
How was the orgy ?
Did you score ?
The high point of the evening
was when I reduced her to tears .
That-a-boy schmucko .
Hey , when are we movin ' on ?
Tomorrow .
The day after .
Soon .
Peggy Ann Snow , Peggy Ann Snow ,
please let me follow ,
where ever you go .
Why 'd you close the door ?
I 'm contemplating taking a piss ,
do you mind ?
Ooh , fancy yancy .
Hey stick your head out here one sec .
Was you thinkin ' about her ?
... stuff like that .
So how long did you work with this Merlin guy ?
I worked for him , years .
But uh , he taught me everything .
But I never performed .
Never on my own .
Why not ?
Probably afraid I 'd fail .
Dope .
It wasn 't ' til the week he took really sick .
And uh , he begged me
that I got the guts to try .
Did you bring any tricks up with you .
No .
I don 't do tricks .
Tricks means something set up beforehand .
A box with a fake lid .
A stacked deck of cards .
I don 't do that .
Will you just use whatever 's available ?
Yeah .
Ah .
Here .
Amaze me .
A stone ?
Oh come on will ya .
Well that was available .
Oh , do it again .
Do it again .
Certainly .
Oh , come on .
Okay .
You bastard .
I really love magic .
No magic , it 's just skill .
All explainable .
I don 't think I want to believe that .
Can you explain everything ?
Pretty much .
What can 't you explain .
Look I don 't want to get into this .
Magic 's just to entertain .
You 're not supposed to take it seriously .
What can 't you explain ?
Merlin , his wife was his assistant before me .
They were close .
They really cared .
Those last days in the hospital with her
he claimed he could read her mind .
You believe that don 't you ?
I don 't know .
I want to I guess .
See in their act ,
they used to do a lot of phony telepathy crap .
Mostly cards .
Then at the end they both wanted to do it for real .
To prove to each other how much they cared ,
is how he put it .
Do you know
the exact procedures they did and everything ?
Sure .
Look , I don 't want to get into this .
Oh , it 'll be fun .
Come on .
I 'd fail .
So what .
I don 't want you thinkin bad of me let 's say .
Okay .
Forget the whole thing .
I 'm trying to get away from pressure , please .
So who 's putting you under pressure ?
Not me .
Just thought it might be a kick .
But it 's forgotten .
Now we 've each shuffled a deck , okay ?
Now you take mine .
So ...
just spread your cards like this .
Fine .
Okay .
Now take one card , any card .
Look at it .
And remember it .
Now what ?
Now come on , you must really look at it .
I 'm looking , I 'm looking ,
don 't be mad .
Okay .
Just concentrate on that one card .
Now gather your cards up .
Place the card back face down .
Good .
Just cut the cards once .
Just take my deck .
Look for your card .
When you find it ,
take it out .
Tell me when you 've found it .
Okay .
Okay ?
What happens now ?
What happened with Merlin was uh ,
she put the card next to her heart .
And uh , he went through her deck kind of like this .
Uh ...
What 's my card ?
I don 't know .
You must really think hard .
Okay .
Okay , I 'm thinking really hard .
Well ?
I 'm sorry .
Well don 't stop .
I 'm concentrating my ass off .
Okay .
My God it 's red isn 't it ?
It 's red .
Maybe it is , maybe it isn 't .
I give away nothing .
Come on concentrate ,
just concentrate .
Hey .
Show me .
We came close , what the hell .
Sit down Peg .
Get back down .
That was your fault .
You started out fine .
But then you let me drift .
Jesus Cork , forget it .
I was in bad shape in New York , Peg ,
and I had to run .
Where do you go when there 's no place to go ?
You go home .
Except there was nothing but empty houses
and old cemeteries .
And I figured I 'd stop by here
and ask your folks about you .
Where were you living , what city , how many kids ?
Never expected to find you here .
I 've loved you all my goddamn life .
I needed a piece of good news about Peggy Ann Snow .
Shuffle the goddamn cards fast .
We 're gonna do it right this time .
I just know we will , because we both want it a lot .
Give me your deck .
Take my deck .
Spread the cards .
Take your card .
Pick it out .
Look at it .
Put it back on top .
Now , cut the deck once .
Take my deck , look for your card .
When you find it tell me .
Look at me .
Should I think now .
Yes , very hard .
I am .
You 're not , I can tell by your eyes your not .
Well I 'm frightened is why .
Nothing to be afraid of .
If it goes bad .
It won 't go bad ,
not if two people want something as much as this .
There must be nothing in your mind but your card .
Nothing in your mind but ...
What ?
My card .
Concentrate .
Just think , think hard .
Is it ...
Please is it ...
Is it the three of clubs ?
The three of clubs ?
I didn 't fail .
I 'll bet they don 't give
service like that at Grossinger 's .
Drop in again in 15 years .
Why the jokes ?
I 'm kind of feeling my way along .
I never fooled around before .
True .
I guess sex wasn 't that big a deal in my life .
What about Duke ?
Mainly he blew in my ear a lot .
True .
I deceived him into thinking it drives me mad .
He tongues away at me
and I moan a lot but ...
secretly I 'm making a grocery list .
Oh , I can be a very crappy lady
if I put my mind to it .
Come here .
Let 's you and me take off .
Just us .
You don 't care for Duke and you know it .
I dump Duke ,
and you 'd leave Fats ,
that 's your offer ?
Yeah , just say the word and we 'll go .
A man appears after 15 years .
Says run away with me .
A girl ought to at least
be able to take a bubble bath .
Think about it , right ?
Why in the hell were you so shy all those years ago , huh ?
Hey what do you say sports fans .
What 's the matter ?
Getting your period ?
Feeling kinda blue .
I miss the city bad .
Oh the country grows on you .
So does fungus .
I told you once already we 'd leave .
When ?
When I want to , now drop it .
What 's so great here ?
Tell me that .
Simmer down okay ?
Okay .
Hey , how 's this for a solution ?
You stay around here and turn hayseed
and I 'll head back to Manhattan .
I take it the silence means no ?
Discussion 's over .
That 's all .
I want out of here !
Simmer the hell down !
Just because ...
Watch it mister !
Just because some ...
You 've been warned !
Just because some sagging bitch of an ingenue
drops her pants for you !
Shut up !
Corky , you do it so good .
You 're even better than the garbage men .
Hey Ben ,
how do you like it ?
I think it 's going to be terrific .
What 's with Gangrene ?
Blue Cross repossess your tongue ?
Come on in , shut up .
Come on in Ben , I 'll do the whole routine for you ?
How the hell did you ever find me .
You 're amazing .
I 'll bet it was that kid cab driver .
He must 've called the office and found ya .
Is that right , that 's it ?
Yeah , I told him I was with William Morris .
He looked like a hustler ,
so I gave him a hundred to shut him up .
How much did you give him to talk .
Doesn 't matter .
Right , right , right , right , right .
Right , you 're here , that 's the main thing .
That 's it , right .
Come on , grab yourself a seat .
And uh , watch .
Just remember that I haven 't got this
anywhere near performance level yet .
How long ya been like this kid ?
Like what ?
Oh my God , you don 't think that was for real ?
How 'd you think I rehearse ?
It 's no good .
It 's for the act for Christ sakes !
Watch now .
Ladies and Gentlemen ,
for your viewing pleasure .
My version of the Miser 's Dream .
Was it a wet dream ?
Shut up .
Imagine if you will .
When I have a wet dream all that happens
is I wake up covered with sawdust .
If you don 't stop interrupting
I 'm going to put a contract out on you
with a mafia woodpecker .
Oh , what I wouldn 't give for a woodpecker .
Would you be quiet .
Don 't encourage him , ladies and gentlemen .
It 's really a great beginning , isn 't it Ben .
Is this why you wouldn 't take the medical exam ?
You figured somebody 'd find out ?
Bullshit !
I 'll take the stupid exam !
I was afraid of success like you said .
I needed to get my head on straight .
I 'll take the exam ,
do the show ,
whatever you want .
What I want kid ?
What I want is for you to see somebody .
Who would I see ?
Quit with the games !
Quit with the yelling !
Shut up !
He should show a little grati-fuckin ' - tude .
You been slaving ' away ,
comin ' up with the great new stuff .
That was blockbuster material mister .
When I come back with Woody the Woodpecker ,
they 'll plotz in Vegas .
That 's funny .
Nothin 's funny .
Not anymore .
What are you gonna do ?
I 'm gonna make a few phone calls .
Tell people you mean ?
Corky , you ain 't in control !
Ben ,
you owe me a listen don 't you think ?
Yeah , I was kind of out of control back in the city .
I uh ...
I could feel myself
starting to slip down the iceberg .
So you took off ,
and now you 're fine ?
Sure .
On account of Peg .
The local town pump , terrific knockers .
Look Fats , please .
Come on will ya ?
Sorry .
Um ...
I 've known her ever since high school .
I never figured I 'd have a chance with her , but uh ,
now everything 's changed .
She believes in me .
Listen ...
girls are for down the line kid .
Right now , you gotta let me help you .
I know a lot of people .
Beautiful doctors .
He means headshrinkers .
He just thinks you 're a fruit cake .
He doesn 't , he never said that , he 's on our side .
He 's the villain .
Don 't forget that .
Never forget that .
Hey kid .
I 'm gonna ask you to do something .
It 's a little something
anybody ought to be able to do .
Now if you can do it , fine .
We 'll forget this whole thing .
But if you can 't ,
we 'll think about getting you to see somebody fast .
Is it a deal ?
Name it .
Make Fats shut up
for five minutes .
Five minutes .
I can make him shut up for five years .
Wonderful .
I feel like the village idiot
if you want to know the truth .
Can we talk or is it going to be strictly semaphore ?
How long so far ?
There 's 30 seconds .
Gosh , that 's uh ...
four and a half minutes to go .
Think I 'll make it ?
Don 't happen to have another of those do ya ?
Thanks .
Take two they 're big .
Remember when you said that Ben ?
A pro never forgets his good lines kid .
How long now ?
Coming up to a minute .
Do you think we 'll laugh about this some day ?
We might .
Make a terrific scene
if you ever decide to write your autobiography .
Hey I know what you should call it , um ...
" Failing Upwards " ,
or , " How to Succeed in Show Business ,
by Outliving Everybody " .
Two minutes yet ?
A minute fortyfive .
This is very cruel of you , you know that ?
I don 't mean it to be .
I don 't know if I 'll ever be able to forgive you .
Well , that would be sad .
Time ?
It 's uh ...
two and a half minutes to go .
I can 't make it .
Well , I didn 't think you could .
Hello everybody .
This is Mrs. Norman Main .
My mother thanks you , my father thanks you ,
my sister thanks you , and I thank you .
You have nothing to fear but fear itself .
Nothing to give but blood sweat and tears .
Nothing to lose but your change .
Here he is boys .
Here he is world .
Here 's Fats .
You 're not lettin him outta here .
He 's the villain , don 't forget that .
Hey , I think you better sit down .
Hey kid ,
I have lived through Tallulah Bankhead
and the death of Vaudeville .
I don 't scare easy .
I need my chance .
Your only chance is to get help fast
and that 's what I 'm going to see happens .
Don 't , ever raise a hand to me again .
You 're taking my one chance .
I 'm your one chance .
He 's right .
The Postman 's right .
You 're crazy .
I tried to stop him didn 't I ?
Tried , tried ?
You failed .
God damn it .
Look at me .
You know it 's the hatch for you .
There 's nothing wrong with me .
I know that ,
and you know that .
But all those piss ant dolts who run the world ,
they hate us because we 're special .
They 'll put you somewhere deep and moody .
Don 't talk that way please .
Cut the migraine shit .
Don 't you care about anything ?
Christ , don 't you care about the girl ?
Peg ?
I love Peg .
I hope she loves you too .
So on visiting day she can bring crayons
and the two of you 's can color together .
What do you want from me ?
You know goddamn well what .
I don 't !
Liar .
Tell me !
Weakling .
I 'm not , I 'm not !
Stop the Postman !
I can 't !
Gutless fuck !
Stop the Postman !
How , how with what ?
Me , me , me , me , me !
Cork ?
What 's up , what is it ?
Oh , I meant to ask .
Do you want me make unthaw the asparagus tips ,
or the French-cut green beans ?
Either .
No fair .
You 're the man
you 've got to make the decision .
Asparagus tips .
Hey what are you doing in the woods ?
Walkin ' , thinkin ' .
About me ?
You changin' your mind about me ?
Jesus no .
Better not you bastard .
Well what is it ?
My head , you broke it .
Well what 'll I do ?
Can 't think , help me .
I will don 't worry .
I 'll take care .
Ahh ...
You 're hurtin ' me .
Sorry .
There you are , that should do it .
That better ?
I guess .
Good .
All right .
Does it show .
Uh ...
Well , I 'll slip you into your overall outfit with a cap .
And uh , nobody will be able to tell a thing .
Hey Fats ?
Yeah .
I 've been doin some thinking .
What would you say if I uh ...
if I called the police and told ?
You ain 't being logical .
Look , Gangrene was taken care of
because he was going to have you put away .
If you tell the cops ,
they 'll have you put away .
Well what 'll we do with him ?
Bring me any identification he 's got on him .
Why ?
Time for a little dip .
After dinner get yourself some stones
and stuff ' em in his pockets .
But I 'm not that strong a swimmer .
Just dog paddle out to the middle
and drop him down .
I know this lake .
There 's snapping turtles out there .
Everybody said that .
Once there was a water moccasin scare .
I don 't care if the Loch Ness monster 's out there ,
and he 's ravenous .
Do it beautifully .
Hello ?
Good morning .
Coffee 's on .
Coffee 's ready .
Good .
Careful .
Uh , Duke got home very late last night .
He didn 't much like the idea
of me being here alone with a man .
He 's watching us now .
Uh , do you think it 's wise
for me to come up there now ?
I think he wants to watch us together .
Oh .
Give me five minutes .
Hey .
Has he got a telescope ?
Because if he doesn 't ,
I 'd like to say that
going to bed with you is maybe
the best three things that ever happened to me .
And I 'd love some coffee .
And I adore you .
And I take it with cream and sugar .
And your breasts belong in the Louvre ,
which is a museum in Paris
that I plan on visiting with you
once you get wise
and decide to leave the old ear blower .
Are you ever somethin ' .
Hello ?
We 're in the kitchen .
Hi Duke .
How are you ?
Come on in , sit down .
Yeah , thanks .
Doing okay .
You take your coffee how ?
Everything .
Sorry I wasn 't here to greet you .
Help with the entertaining and all .
But somebody 's got to earn a living .
You 're still in real estate right ?
No , I gave that up .
It was dull .
What I really like is the out a doors .
Go fishing , hunting .
That probably seems dull to someone like you .
No , not at all .
Fine , thanks .
And I do a little selling ' nowadays .
Sundries , like that .
I 'm surprised Peg here didn 't bring you up to date .
Well she may have .
The truth is ,
once I start drinking wine ,
you can forget about me .
Hey Duke , that stuff you sell ?
You don 't happen to have a penis do you ?
My last one caught Dutch Elm Disease
and it 's murder getting an erection .
God damn , that 's clever .
Don 't tell schmucko .
Tell me .
'Cause I 'm the talent .
Shhh ...
Do you travel a lot in your work ?
How do you do that ?
I mean that 's terrific .
I 'm really glad you 're here for me to see this .
Are you going to be good ?
I mean it .
You promise ?
Okay .
Ask him if he 's glad I 'm here too ?
Yeah , the both of you .
Thank you .
How long are you going to be ?
Quick as I can .
As long as it takes me to board up those far cabins .
Don 't stay out too long .
You 'll get soaked .
How 'd I do .
Just unbelievable .
Too bad Fats wasn 't here .
He might of been a little help .
Gotten a couple of laughs .
You 're always unbelievable .
Oh , brains as well as boobs .
Corky , do you drive a Rolls ?
No .
Well there 's somebody 's white Rolls parked down there .
Shit .
It 's gotta be Gangrene 's .
Why would he leave it though .
Who 's is it ?
My agent .
He 's rich as hell .
But still you just don 't leave an $ 80,000 car and walk away .
He must have come looking for me .
Looking for you ?
Yeah .
He 's left the keys .
Yeah , look if I level with you ,
you won 't let this get around ?
I 'm in hiding .
A lot of career problems .
I haven 't been behaving all that normal .
Well can you find out what 's happened to him .
This cars been here a couple of hours .
Yeah , I 'll sure as hell try .
Hey , would you mind getting it unstuck ?
Me driving an $ 80,000 car ,
I 'd mind that a lot .
Sadie ?
It 's me .
Is he in ?
Please .
Don 't yell at me Goddamn it .
I 'm sick of hearing about my erratic behavior .
How the hell did you ever find me .
I tipped that bastard cabbie
so he wouldn 't tell .
We were on a long walk
is why you didn 't find anybody .
Never mind who the we is ,
finish about the car .
Ha , ha .
I 'd love to have seen that .
You hitchhiking a ride to Grossinger 's .
Why didn 't you have ' em come and un-stick the car .
Quit yelling .
I should a known ,
nobody touches your Rolls but a Rolls man .
Sorry .
Duke 's on his way .
Yes sir .
That was the we .
Yes sir , a lot .
It 's not ridiculous .
We grew up together .
Yes she 's married .
But I think she 's leaving him for me .
The marriage was over .
I 'm not talking about puppy love Ben .
I 'm talking about salvation .
Some fish .
Some fish he takes me for .
Your old pal I 'm talking about .
I suspected .
His story 's so full a holes .
Why do you keep repeating that ?
So a car is here , who care ?
Besides , Corky agrees with you .
It 's a crazy story ,
but there it is .
Some happy coincidence .
A guy drives 90 miles
and you and Corky just happen to be
off in the woods when he 's snooping ' .
You put out for him in the woods did ya ?
I love it when you 're drinking .
Well why didn 't you tell me
about this Goddamn legendary walk before ?
No comment .
Listen ,
I know his story 's bullshit
because I got the car out of the mud
and it was nothing .
If I can do it , anybody can .
Maybe he tried .
Maybe he couldn 't .
He 's old .
Corky never said he was old .
He must of to me .
When ?
When we were having dinner , probably .
He got squiffed fast and flaked out .
That 's what he said earlier .
And how did you know he was old , did you see him ?
Answer me , I 'm talking to you !
No , I didn 't see him .
Why not ?
He must 've wrung the bell .
I mean the guy drives 90 miles ,
he 's gonna ring the Goddamn doorbell , wouldn 't you agree ?
I didn 't hear any bell .
Now quit this .
Why not ?
What were you doin ' that was so ...
Did he ring while you were screwing ' , is that it ?
That is it isn 't it ?
No it isn 't .
Why didn 't you invite him in to watch ?
Shut your dirty mouth .
Did you screw Corky ?
No !
I 'll pound you all day , you keep lying !
I 'm not lying !
The truth , the goddamn truth !
Did you fuck him ?
No I didn 't !
But I wanted to .
Come on , it 'll be fun .
If you don 't like fishin
I 'll let you row .
Just had a good talk with Peg .
Like to have one with you now .
I 'll grab a jacket .
Where is Peg ?
She 's in town making a decision , she said .
Oh .
What are you doin ' that for ?
Uh , habit .
Hey , we trust each other don 't we ?
Of course .
You seem upset .
Should I be ?
Get in the front .
What are you lookin ' for ?
Nothin ' .
You 're the one wants to fish .
Why don 't you try over there .
Here I 'll do the rowing .
I know the best holes .
When I get us there you can take over .
I 'm not much on booze .
I told you that .
You told me a lot of things .
What 's that supposed to mean ?
Peg said you screwed her last night .
Damn .
I told her to keep it a secret .
You think it 's funny do you ?
Is that why you brought me out here ?
Try to get me to admit to something that never happened ?
If it is I 'd like to go back in now Duke .
What she said was ,
she wanted to go to bed with you .
I 'm loosin ' her Corky ,
And I don 't know what to do .
All she does is talk about you Duke .
You 're not losing anybody .
What I said before ,
about quitting the real estate business ,
there was never any real estate business to quit .
She came in when I was on top .
And she stuck with me all the way down .
Goddamn it .
Oh , that 's heavy .
Duke , I said I 'd like to go back in now .
This feels like a whale .
God , I 'm cold ,
let 's get the hell in .
It 's comin ' loose .
Hey you 're breakin ' my pole .
I 'm trying to help you , that 's all .
Well don 't help .
It 's comin ' now .
It 's comin ' .
Goddamn log .
Any of that scotch left ?
Thought you didn 't like booze ?
I 'm freezing my nuts off , that 's all .
Thanks .
I wonder who he is .
See what his wallet says .
Jesus Christ ,
I was thinking ' he might be your Rolls Royce guy .
Gangrene ?
You must be kidding ' me .
He 's about 6 ' 3 " .
Nothin ' .
He 's stripped clean .
It doesn 't make sense .
Must be some identification .
Jesus Christ , he might still be alive .
Fantastic .
I 'll do the kiss of life .
You run up to the house , call Normandy Hospital .
Tell ' em to get over .
Right .
And stay at the house 'til they get there
so you can direct 'em straight here .
Gotcha .
Ben Greene .
Gangrene .
Son of a bitch .
He is the Rolls guy .
Oh .
Jesus .
Don 't panic .
My God , what have you done !
I said don 't panic .
My God , what am I going to do ?
Well pick me up dumb dumb and I 'll tell ya .
Listen to me .
Well sit down then dummy .
Alright .
You 're gonna zoom to my suitcase
and whip out one of those
nice long pieces of canvas .
Well clean my face and you won 't throw up .
Okay .
You 're gonna take the canvas
and you 're gonna wrap part around Duke here ,
and part of it around Gangrene .
Then you 're gonna get a nice big rock
and wrap the rest around it .
Take that out a my mouth .
Then you 're gonna row out
and dump the bundle over the side .
And if you do it right ,
I 'll be able to say atta boy schmucko .
Two birds with one stone .
Hi .
You 've had quite a day I guess .
Whatever .
Where 's Duke .
We had a blow out .
He tried to get me to admit we 'd gone to bed together .
But uh ...
when he couldn 't he told me he was going to go hunting
and I should get the hell out
by the time he got back .
Are you coming with me ?
I gotta know .
Who wins ,
me or Duke ?
If I 'm a prize ,
then you 're the winner .
And as soon as Duke gets back
and I can tell him in person that I 'm leaving ,
we can take off .
Gee you know I , I ...
I don 't think you should put yourself
through a big emotional scene like that , do you ?
Well , I gotta leave Duke with his pride .
We spent a lotta years together and uh ...
he 's gotta understand that he didn 't fail .
We failed together .
So let 's the both of us pack okay .
Don 't try arguing me out of this .
He 's got to be home soon .
He can 't hunt at night time right ?
Okay .
Oh , my God .
She 's leaving Duke for you .
Fan-fucking-gradly , fan-fucking-tastic .
Thank you sports fans .
Well where are we off to ?
Now don 't get emotional about this .
About what , about what ?
I think maybe there 's just going to be
two of us on the honeymoon .
What 's the punch line ?
You 're gonna leave me behind ?
Come on buddy , quit the kiddin ' .
My head 's on straight on now .
I want to get to know her , that 's all .
Take her places .
Show her things .
Paris , maybe , like that .
The Eiffel Tower .
The Louvre .
You know ?
Schmucko , you 've never been to Paris .
What 's this show her routine ?
I 'll be good .
You 'll see .
I wanna see Paris too .
You want me to come crawling ?
You want me to beg ?
Okay , this is me , Fats ,
and I 'm beggin ' .
It 's not easy for me either .
It is .
It is easy .
You wont be alone .
I 'll tell .
What will you tell ?
Everything .
I will .
I swear .
In the middle of the act ,
one night , when you don 't expect it .
I 'll scream , there 's bodies in Lake Melody .
I don 't see that happening .
I 'm doing a single now .
Duke ?
How 'd it go ?
Duke understand .
We haven 't talked yet .
You mean he isn 't back yet .
Christ Peg .
Got kinda scary up there .
And I wanted a drink ,
but I didn 't much wanna drink alone .
Well let 's just go .
Let 's get the hell out .
Send him a telegram .
I 'm sorry , my mind 's made up .
Besides , he can 't be much longer .
You don 't know that .
He was drinking heavy when he left here .
Did he take a flashlight with him ?
Did you notice ?
All I noticed
was that big Goddamn elephant gun he was carrying
when he hinted I vacate the premises .
Come on ,
it 's stupid waiting around .
Then I 'm stupid .
I didn 't say you were stupid .
I said waiting was .
I 'm aware of your opinion on the subject .
Well try agreeing with me for once .
Instead of being stubborn .
Give it a rest Cork .
Aaah ...
Sweet mystery of life
at last I 've found you .
Fasten your seatbelts everybody .
It 's going to be a bumpy night .
I 'm here to save you two from yourselves .
Want me to do something dazzling .
You do magic too ?
Corky does magic .
I only do tricks .
Hey I got just the thing Peg .
Bring me a couple a decks of cards
and I 'll read your mind .
What do you mean ?
I 'll pull the same card from your deck
that you pull from mine .
That 's not a trick .
You can 't do that .
Sure .
You just peek at the bottom card after shuffling
and it 's easy as apple pie .
Corky makes a big deal production number out of it sometimes .
Like when he 's got some bimbo stewardess he wants to screw .
He makes him think their minds have touched .
Never fails .
You 'll never know how many people
want to believe in magic .
Oh shit .
Peg .
Peg please .
Please , please come ...
Were you laughing every second .
Please , please .
Was I funny you bastard son of a bitch ?
Oh ...
Let me explain .
Hey , hey .
Jesus .
Listen to me you schmuck .
You gotta please just answer me one small question ?
Why 'd you think I blew the whistle ?
Ah , because I was leaving .
Because you were jealous .
Wrong schmucko .
I did it because I could .
See ?
Why didn 't you stop me ?
Answer , you didn 't because you couldn 't .
Look at him .
He still doesn 't understand .
Better sit down kid
while I hit you with an explanation .
Ever since we got together ,
I laid low .
It was best for the act .
I let you share the limelight .
If there 's one thing about me , I 'm big .
But then earlier today ,
when I begged ya ,
pleaded not to be left behind
and you pissed ice water all over me ,
well , that tore it .
If I 'm boring you ,
please walk around .
I don 't care .
Fats don 't start in on me .
Please don 't .
Listen , I took a failure .
With the charm of Tricky Dickey Nixon .
I made us skyrocket .
It 's not gonna be you and her ,
it 's gonna stay you and me .
Except from now on even that 's changed .
It 's me and you .
You said I 've got a weak stomach .
You look tired .
I 'm not .
Then what are you yawning for ?
I 'm not yawning .
You gotta wake you up .
Crawl around .
That should help .
You think ?
Hey yeah , it does help .
Say thank you Fats .
Thanks .
Thanks Fats .
With feeling , like I 'm doing .
I 'm filled with greatest fucking joy .
Gee you 've got talent after all .
Let 's see what else you can do .
Fats says smile .
Fats says frown .
Fats says touch the ceiling .
Fats says spin around .
Fats says get a knife .
What ?
Get a knife .
Come on .
From my suitcase .
Yeah .
I know where it is .
I wonder what we could do with it ?
Hey , I could whittle something .
I 'm good at that , and fast too , name it .
No .
I 'm looking for something with a little more pizzazz .
Yeah , yeah , yeah .
Don 't do it .
You really love old Peg don 't ya ?
Oh please , don 't kill her .
Schmucko easy .
I wouldn 't dream of
depriving you of that pleasure .
No , I can 't do it !
There 's that old bug-a-boo of yours again .
lack of confidence .
I won 't and you can 't make me !
Wow , I really stepped on a corn that time .
If I can 't make ya , I can 't make ya .
How 's your head Cork ?
Fine !
Thought you might be getting ' a migraine .
No !
Shows how wrong you can be .
Open those baby blues .
Looks to me like one of those gut wrenchers .
It 's getting bad fast .
Please !
Drilling right into the brain is it ?
Surprise .
Came fast .
It can go fast .
Yeah .
Oh yes .
Not so deep anymore ?
No , not so deep .
It 'll all be gone soon .
Uh ... Thanks Fats .
Want it a hundred times worse ,
and a hundred days long ?
No .
Then take the knife on up the hill lover .
And kiss the girl goodbye .
Duke ?
I left schmucko down at the cabin .
Open up huh ?
You and me gotta have a quick palaver .
Corky there 's nothin ' to say .
I told ya ,
he 's at the cabin .
You and me are the only ones can straighten this out .
Go away Cork .
Fats .
All right , go away Fats .
That 's better .
At least we know who we are now .
Hey , I 've got a present that 'll make you smile .
Promise it will .
He made it for you Peg .
For you to remember him by .
See , he 's leaving now
and he wants you to have this .
Have what ?
A wooden heart .
He whittled it for you
before he sent me up .
He 's quick with his hands .
Leave it outside the door .
Take his heart Peg .
So he 'll know you don 't feel contempt for him .
Oh , I never felt that .
At least that 's something .
I 'll leave it by the door .
Bye .
Wait a minute , you didn 't leave .
Brains as well as boobs .
Anytime you feel like
playing with my levers you 'll call ?
Sure , sure .
Peggy Ann Snow ,
please let me follow
wherever you go .
She liked my heart .
She smiled when she picked it up .
She looked so pleased and everything .
I made her happy .
Me ?
No tricks or anything .
What 's wrong .
I don 't know how to say this ,
since I haven 't got a stomach ,
but my stomach hurts .
Bad ?
Gettin ' bad .
Gettin ' real bad .
Yeah .
What 's goin ' on ?
We 're dying I think is what it is ?
Dyin ' ?
Yeah ,
I put the knife deep in me .
Christ it 's spreadin ' .
Yeah .
Don 't leave me here alone .
Don 't worry .
Can you get over here .
I 'll try .
Put me flat .
Here .
Why didn 't you leave ?
Go with her when you had the chance ?
She 'd never of gone with me .
She 'd have turned me down .
I couldn 't even get her to open the door by myself .
It was never me .
Always us .
Schmucko .
Us was you .
What ?
It was you all the time .
I hope I don 't die first is all .
I think we 'll go together .
Chances are .
Hey Cork ?
Hey it 's me .
I changed my mind .
Let 's give it a whack okay ?
See how it goes ?
What do ya say .
I 'm warning you Cork ,
don 't play hard to get with me .
'Cause I 'm a woman see ,
and I can always change my mind again .
You may not get this oppor-fuckin ' - tunity tomorrow .